Oh, hey, you guys?
喔，嘿，你们大家
I couldn't get a reservation for the night of my birthday..
我生日当天晚上订不到餐厅…
so we'll have to do dinner Thursday night.
所以我们要改到星期四晚上
- Thursday? But that's Halloween. - So?
-星期四？但是那是万圣节耶！ -那又怎样？
It's just spooky, that's all.
只不过是很诡异而已
So, is Mike coming to dinner?
那，麦克也会跟我们吃晚餐吗？
No. It's my first birthday with a boyfriend, and he has to work.
不会，我第一次可以跟男朋友过生日 他却要上班
I'd get mad at him, but I think it's too soon to show my true colors.
我很想对他发脾气 但是我想这会太快露出马脚
I would make the reservation for five. One of us has to stay with Emma.
那这样我会只订五个人的位子 我们其中一个要留下来照顾艾犸
- Which one of us should go to dinner? - Rachel!
-我们该谁去晚餐呢？ -瑞秋！
Actually, I was thinking maybe both of us could go.
事实上，我想或许我们两个都可以去
Oh. Yeah.
哦，真好！
Thanks. I'll put a lot of extra thought into your gift.
谢谢，我会多用点心准备你的礼物
All right, so great, we can all go now.
好了，太棒了，我们全部都可以去
That is fun! Hey! You know what?
真棒！嘿！你们知道吗？
We all haven't been together, the six of us, in such a long time.
我们六个人已经很久没有这样在一起了
What are you talking about? We're together now.
你在说什么呢？ 我们现在就在一起啊？
Mon? Chandler's not here.
摩妮卡，钱德并不在这里
Oh, dear God.
喔，老天
The One With Phoebe's Birthday Dinner
本集播出：菲比的生日晚餐
rianystar压制iPod-MP4
（土尔沙）
Hello. It's nice to see our team together for the first time.
大家好，很高兴第一次我们全员到齐
Now, before we get started, are there any questions?
现在，在我们开始之前 有任何问题吗？
- Yes. Ken, is it? - That's right.
-是的，肯，对吧？ -没错
Is it true the reason you're in Tulsa is, you fell asleep in a meeting..
听说你会来土尔沙的原因 是因为你在开会的时候睡着…
and took the job without realizing what you were saying yes to?
然后随口就答应接下 这份你根本搞不清楚的工作，是吗？
Well, don't believe everything you hear, Ken.
嗯，别道听涂说，肯
But yeah, that's true.
但是没错，那是真的
All right, let's get started by taking a look at last quarter's figures.
好了，我们先开始看一下上一季的数字
Claudia, aren't you supposed to blow smoke up the boss's ass?
克劳蒂亚，你不是应该要 先问一下老板可不可以抽烟吗？
- I'm sorry. Does the smoke bother you? - No. I smoked for years. Then I quit.
-我很抱歉，你介意我抽烟吗？ -不，我抽了好多年，然后戒了
Right now, I can't remember why.
现在也忘了为什么要戒
You're not allowed to smoke in this office, right?
在办公室不准抽烟的，不是吗？
Yes, in Oklahoma it's legal to smoke in offices with 15 people or less.
可以的，在奥克拉荷马 在十五人以下的办公室 抽烟是合法的
- Would you like one? - Would Joey like two pizzas?
-你要来一根吗？ -乔伊想要吃两个披萨吗？
You don't know what I'm talking about.
你不知道我的意思吗？
All right, look. I don't smoke anymore.
好了，听着，我戒烟了
But if the rest of you want to light up, go ahead, it's fine.
如果你们其他人也想抽 请便，没关系的
So, you all smoke, then?
原来你们全部都抽烟
You know, it's almost rude that I'm not smoking.
你们知道吗？ 我不抽烟反而看起来很没礼貌
- That's not true. If you don't want.. - Ken, please!
-没那回事，如果你不想… -肯，拜托！
No, I can't. I can't smoke. If I smoke, my wife would kill me.
不，不行，我不能抽烟 如果我抽烟，我老婆会杀了我
I'm sorry, but isn't your wife back in New York?
不好意思，但是你老婆不是在纽约吗？
I've always liked you, Ken.
我一直都很喜欢你，肯
Trick or treat.
不给糖就捣蛋
- Hey. - And "treat" it is.
-嘿 -真是好吃啊！
Wow. So glad I changed.
哇，幸好我有换衣服
I almost wore my threadbare robe that can't contain my breasts.
我差一点就穿上那件 连胸部都遮不住的破睡袍
This is not what I'm wearing. I'm ovulating..
我不是要穿这件出门 我正在排卵…
and Chandler's gonna be home. So, I thought we would try before dinner.
而钱德很快就回来了 所以我想我们可以在晚餐前试一下
Oh, I thought we'd all go over together.
喔，我以为我们全部要一起过去
All right, I'll just meet you there at dinner.
好了，我们晚餐见
Unless, I mean, if it helps, I could stay and watch.
除非，我是说，如果有帮助的话 我可以留下来当观众
- No! - Well, I didn't want to anyway.
-不必！ -喔，反正我也不想看
You know, just thought I'd be polite and offer.
你知道的，我只是想要 礼貌性地问一声
Wait, does this mean you'll be late?
等一下，这表示你们会迟到吗？
We haven't seen each other in over a week.
我们已经超过一个星期没有见面了
We'll probably be the first ones there.
我们可能会是第一个到的
Okay. See you there. Happy humping.
好了，待会见，祝你们搞的愉快
Hey. Well, hey!
嘿！
Wow, somebody smoked out here?
哇，有人在这里抽烟吗？
My God, don't people know you're not allowed to smoke in public spaces?
天啊，难道他们不晓得 在公共场所是不可以抽烟的吗？
Actually, in Oklahoma smoking's legal in offices with fewer than 15 people.
事实上，在奥克拉荷马 在少于十五人的办公室抽烟是合法的
Oh, you smoked.
喔，是你抽的！
No. I just happen to know a lot of trivia about smoking in different states.
不是，我只是刚好知道 不同州的抽烟规定
For example, in Hawaii, cigarettes are called lei-lana-lukus.
例如，在夏威夷 香烟叫做雷拉纳路卡斯
- Oh, Chandler, you stink of cigarettes! - Do you think Monica will smell it?
-喔，钱德，你身上都是臭烟味！ -你想摩妮卡会闻得到吗？
Are you kidding? That woman has the nose of a bloodhound.
你在开玩笑吗？ 那女人的鼻子像狗一样灵
And the breasts of a Greek goddess.
胸部像希腊女神一样美
Phoebe?
菲比？
I'm gonna go.
我要走了
Okay. Something to cover the smell.
好了，有什么可以掩盖味道
Oven cleaner.
炉灶清洁剂
Unscented.
无添加香味
Welcome home.
欢迎回来
I've missed you.
我好想你
- You want to join me in the bedroom? - No, thanks, I'm good.
-想要跟我进房间吗？ -不，谢了，不用
Okay. So you want to play it that way, do you?
好的，你想要这样玩，是吗？
Well, you know what, actually, I just got off a plane..
嗯，你知道吗？事实上 我才刚下飞机…
so I'm feeling gross. I should take a shower.
觉得有点脏 我应该先洗个澡
- Come here, you don't need a shower. - All right, the truth is..
-过来，你不需要洗澡 -好的，事实上是…
I soiled myself during some turbulence.
我在乱流的时候弄脏了自己
What do I smell? I smell smoke.
什么味道？我闻到烟味
Did you smoke?
你有抽烟吗？
Yes. But I just had one.
有，但是只抽了一根
Two.
两根
Two tiny cigarettes. Okay, five.
两小根，好吧，五根
A pack. Two pack.. A carton.
一包，两包…一条
Three big fat cartons in two days!
两天抽三大条香烟！
But it's over. I've made a decision, I'm not gonna smoke anymore.
但是都结束了，我已经决定 再也不要抽烟了
Well, those are for you.
嗯，那是要送给你的
All right. Well, we'll just see you when you get here. Bye.
好的，嗯，到时候见，拜
Oh, that was my mom. She's stuck in terrible traffic.
喔，那是我妈，她遇到大塞车
That is now the third sign that I should not leave Emma.
这是第三个征兆 告诉我不应该离开艾犸
- What are the other two? - Well, the first one is, I don't want to.
-另外两个征兆是什么呢？ -嗯，第一个是，我不想要
And second one, I'm not going.
第二个是，我不要去
I know this is the first time we're leaving the baby.
我知道这是我们第一次离开艾犸
I know how hard it is for you. But..
我知道这对你很困难，但是…
But everything's gonna be fine. I mean, my mom is gonna be with her.
但是一切都会很好的 我是说，我妈会在这里照顾她
- She's great with kids. - She is?
-她很会照顾小孩的 -真的吗？
Yeah.
真的
What about Monica?
那摩妮卡呢？
You only hear Monica's side of that. Okay, that little fatso was a terror!
你都只听她说的话 那个肥妹是个恐怖份子！
- I just don't think I can do it. - Know what? You can and you should.
-我只是不认为我办得到 -你知道吗？你应该、也办得到
Really, it will be good for you.
真的，这对你是有帮助的
In fact, you know what?
事实上，你知道吗？
Go ahead to the restaurant, and I will wait for my mom..
你先去餐厅，我留下来等我妈…
and then I'll meet you there. No, no, really, you should go. Go out.
然后我再过去找你们 真的，你应该过去，出去
Really, the world is your oyster. Kick up your heels. Paint the town red!
真的，这世界是你的 甩开高跟鞋，挥洒出自己的颜色！
- You need to learn some new slang. - I'm serious. Come on, you should go.
-你是该学些新的广告词 -我是说真的，走吧，你该走了
Here. No, just go.
来，去吧
- Well.. - No, no! You know what?
-那… -不，不！你知道吗？
You're not getting back in there! The baby's fine. Now, scram!
你别想要进去！宝宝没事的！ 现在快走吧！
Yeah, hit the bricks!
是啊，迈开步伐走吧！
Tell your story walking!
什么都免惊，向前行！
I was just going to say that I left my keys.
我只是要说，我忘记带钥匙了
Holy moley, are we in a pickle now!
老天啊，这下我们惨了！
Where is everyone? They're 40 minutes late.
他们人呢？已经迟到四十分钟了
- I know. - I'm starving.
-我知道 -我饿死了
I knew we were coming here tonight. I ate nothing all day.
我知道我们今晚要来这里 所以我整天都没有吃东西
What about me? I only had one lunch today.
那我怎么说呢？我才吃一顿午餐而已
So, are we expecting the rest of our party shortly?
那么，其他的贵宾很快就会到临吗？
Yes, they are expected presently. Yeah.
是的，我们衷心期盼他们的即将到临 是啊
Their arrival is in the offing.
他们即将现身了
Right. We have a table for two available.
好的，我们也有两人座的位置
- Perhaps you'd.. - No, they're coming.
-或许你们… -不用了，他们要来了
We're waiting right here.
我们就在这里等
Joseph!
乔瑟夫！（乔伊全名）
One needn't worry. They shan't be long.
没有“您”需要担心 他们应该不会太“漫长”
It's just that we do have some large parties waiting.
我们有一些人在等着要用餐
Oh, one really does have a stick up one's ass, doesn't one?
喔！有“您”真的 需要这样机机车车的吗？
Why would you start smoking again? It's so bad for you.
你为什么又开始抽烟？ 它对身体那么不好
It's only been two days. That's not enough time to..
我才开始抽了两天 没那么快就…
That's totally unrelated.
这跟那个一点关系都没有
How can you smoke in this day and age? Have you not seen that ad?
什么时代了怎么还会抽烟呢？ 你没有看过反烟广告吗？
Where the little kid walks through Grandpa? It's chilling!
那个小孩走穿过他爷爷那个广告 真是吓死人了！
I messed up. It was a meeting. Everybody was smoking.
我搞砸了，不过是一个会议 每个人都在抽烟啊！
So what? Don't you have any willpower?
那又如何？你难道没有任何意志力吗？
Willpower? I've watched home movies of you eating Ding Dongs..
意志力？ 我看过你在吃巧克力的家庭录影带…
without taking the tinfoil off!
…连包装纸都来不及打开！
You said that was sexy!
你说那看起来很性感！
Okay, look, can we just drop this? I'm not gonna smoke again.
好了，好了，可不可以算了？ 我不会再抽烟了
That's right, because I forbid you to smoke again.
没错，因为我禁止你抽烟
You forbid me?
你禁止我？
I've flown a long way to see my loving wife.
我大老远飞回来见我可爱的老婆
Is she here, by the way?
对了，她在吗？
Chandler, don't joke with me. Okay? I'm very, very upset right now.
钱德，别开玩笑，好吗？ 我现在非常非常地不高兴
- Is this the most upset you could be? - I think so.
-现在是你最不高兴的时候吗？ -我想应该是的
Well, then I might as well..
那，我何不就…
do this.
这样做
Not really sure what to do now.
不确定接下来要干么
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
我告诉你我们要做什么
We're already late for Phoebe's birthday dinner.
我们要去参加菲比的生日晚餐 我们已经迟到了
So you're going to put out that cigarette..
所以你要把香烟熄掉…
we're gonna put this fight on hold, and go have sex.
我们先暂停吵架 先上床再说
Fine. What?
好，什么？
What, do you have cigarettes in your ears?
怎样？你耳朵是塞了香烟吗？
Sex! This is the last day I'm ovulating. If we don't do it..
上床！今天是我排卵的最后一天 如果我们不做…
we're gonna have to wait until next month!
我们就要等到下个月了！
You're serious?
你是认真的吗？
- Oh, yeah! - All right, fine, I'll do it, but no talking!
-喔，是的！ -随便，做就做，但我不跟你说话！
- And no cuddling. - And no kissing your neck.
-而且没有抱抱 -而且不亲吻你脖子
Oh, good! I hate it when you do that!
喔，很好！反正我也很讨厌你那样做！
And lots of kissing your neck!
那我要尽量亲你的脖子！
Okay, well, the super's not home.
嗯，管理员不在家
But my mother's gonna be here, and she has the key.
但是我妈快到了，她有钥匙
I can't wait that long. You have to do something. Knock that door down!
我等不了那么久，你得想想办法 把门撞倒吧！
I would, but I bruise like a peach.
我也想，但是我就跟桃子一样容易撞伤
Besides, you know, everything's gonna be fine. The baby's sleeping.
而且，你知道一切都会没事的 婴儿在睡觉
- What if she jumps out of the bassinet? - Can't hold her head up, but jumped.
-万一她跳出摇篮呢？ -根本连头都抬不高，还想跳
Oh, my God! I left the water running!
喔，天啊！我水龙头还开着！
You did not leave the water running. Please, pull yourself together, okay?
你没有让水龙头开着 拜托，冷静一点，好吗？
- Well, did I leave the stove on? - You haven't cooked since 1996.
-那，我有把炉子开着吗？ -1996年之后你就没有煮过饭了
Is the window open? If the window's open a bird could fly in and..
窗户有开着吗？如果开着 鸟可能会飞进来然后…
My God, you know what? I think you're right.
天啊，你知道吗？我想你说对了
- Listen. - What? What?
-听 -什么？什么？
A pigeon. No. No, wait, no. An eagle flew in!
是鸽子，不，等等，不 是老鹰飞进去了！
Landed on the stove and caught fire!
飞到炉子上然后烧了起来了！
The baby, seeing this, jumps across the apartment to the mighty bird's aid.
婴儿看到这一切 从公寓这边跳过去帮助老鹰
The eagle, however, misconstrues this as an act of aggression..
而老鹰却误判认为 这是个攻击的行动…
and grabs the baby in its talon.
用爪子捉住婴儿
Meanwhile, the faucet fills the apartment with water.
就在这时候，水龙头的水 充满了整间公寓
Baby and bird, still ablaze, are locked in a death grip..
婴儿跟老鹰还在激战中 双方被死亡的陷阱困住…
swirling around the whirlpool that fills the apartment!
在公寓内的漩涡里旋转着！
Boy, are you gonna be sorry if that's true.
天，如果这一切是真的你就死定了
- Hello. - Hi.
-哈 -嗨
It's been an hour.
已经一个小时了
The maitre d' asked if you'd reconsider switching to a smaller table.
经理要我问你们是否要考虑换到小桌子
Maybe we should just eat now.
或许我们应该先用餐
You can't order until the entire party's arrived. Restaurant policy.
在人还没有到齐之前你们不能点餐 这是餐厅规定
Well, how about this? Another table leaves, right..
好，那如果说另一桌离开了…
but there's still some food left on their plates.
但是他们的餐盘里还有食物…
Okay, what's the restaurant's policy about people eating that?
餐厅有规定不能吃那些食物吗？
- It's frowned upon. - But it happens.
-那是很不合宜的 -但是还是会发生啊
- All right, I got to go to the bathroom. - You can't go.
-好了，我要去厕所 -你不能去
No, no, no. I can't hold this table on my own.
不，不，不 我没有办法自己保住这张桌子
If they ask me to move, I'll cave.
如果他们要我换位子，我会屈服的
Well, if you ask me to stay, I'll pee.
如果你要我留下来，我会尿裤子的
Good evening, miss.
晚安，小姐
Miss?
小姐？
Miss? Miss?
小姐？小姐？
Okay, fine, I'll move. All right. You don't have to manhandle me.
好了，算了，我换位子，好了 你不需要动手动脚的
- Where? - Okay.
-哪里？ -好的
Thank you. Wow.
谢谢，哇
Will you stop staring at us now?
现在你可以停止盯着我们看了吗？
That depends. Will your friend stop drinking olive oil directly from the bottle?
看情况，你朋友可以停止 喝那瓶橄榄油了吗？
Probably not.
或许没办法
Finally. You guys made it.
终于，你们到了
Phoebe, who the hell..?
菲比，这些人是谁…？
What is taking you so long, Come on, let's get it over with!
你是在摸什么摸这么久 快点，我们早做早完成！
In a minute, sweet cakes.
马上好，亲爱的
Spend more time with the tie! That will make a baby.
多花点时间在领带上！ 那样可以生出小孩来
Look, I can't do this. I can't make love to you while we're fighting this way.
听着，我做不到 我没有办法在吵架的时候还跟你做爱
Oh, sure. Now you're Mr. Sensitivity.
喔，是啊，现在你可真敏感纤细
But when you wanted to have sex after my uncle's funeral..
那当初你想在我叔叔丧礼之后做爱时…
That was a celebration of life!
那是庆祝生命！
All right, I'm not gonna do this.
好了，我不想这样做
Is this the way you want our baby to be conceived?
你想要我们的孩子 在这种情况下受孕吗？
No, you're right.
不，你是对的
We shouldn't do it like this.
我们不应该在这种情况下做
For what it's worth, I'm sorry.
反正，我很抱歉
I shouldn't have come down on you so hard about the smoking.
我不应该对你抽烟这件事这样的刁难
So you had a few cigarettes. It's not the end of the world.
你是抽了几根烟，又不代表世界末日
- Really? - Yeah.
-真的？ -是的
You are incredible.
你真不可思议
And listen, I'm not gonna smoke again.
听着，我不会再抽烟了
And if I do, I promise I will hide it so much better from you.
如果我抽，我保证也会 隐藏到让你看不出来
- Want to? - Let's celebrate life!
-想吗？ -我们来庆祝生命！
Okay!
好了！
Oh, God.
喔，天啊
Oh, thank God you're okay.
喔，感谢上帝你没事
I'm sorry we left. Mommy will never leave you again.
我很抱歉我们离开你 妈咪再也不会离开你了
Never, ever, ever again.
再也… 再也不会
Great. So let's get going.
太棒了，我们走吧
I mean it. After what just happened, I'm never leaving her again.
我是说真的，在经历过刚刚的事之后 我再也不会离开她了
I understand. Separation is hard.
我了解，分离是很煎熬的
One time I was about to leave Ross to go to the beauty parlor.
有一次我要离开罗斯去美容院
And he got so upset he took off all his clothes..
他就变得很不开心 他把衣服脱光…
tucked his willy between his legs..
把小鸡鸡夹在双腿间….
and cried out, "Mommy, I'm a girl. Take me with you."
然后哭喊“妈咪，我是女生 带我跟你去”
Somehow, over time, it got easier to be apart from you.
物换星移之后 跟你分开已经变得容易很多了
You are welcome.
不客气
- You know what? Let's not talk. - What?
-你知道吗？我们还是不要说话 -什么？
- I am still so mad at you for smoking! - But you said you forgave me.
-我对你抽烟的事还是很生气！ -但你说你已经原谅我了
It was just a couple of cigarettes, no big deal.
只不过是几根烟，没有什么大不了的
I was ovulating and you said you wouldn't have sex if we were fighting.
我正在排卵，而你却说如果我们在吵架 你是不会跟我做爱的
- You tricked me to get me into bed? - That's right. I got mine.
-你骗我跟你上床？ -没错，我得到我想要的了
I feel so used.
我被利用了
Well, I guess they're not coming. You want to just order?
我想他们不会来了 你想要点了吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
Waiter? All right, this is gonna go fast, so try to keep up.
侍者？好了，我会说很快 所以记好
Risotto with shaved truffles and the rib steak..
意大利扁面配松露切片 然后肋眼牛排…
with the golden chanterelles and the Bordelaise sauce..
加上酥炸鸡油菇和波尔多红酒酱…
unless any of that stuff I just said means "snails."
希望我以上说的那么多东西 没有包括“蜗牛”
It does not.
是没有
Tomato tart, and which of the pastas would you recommend?
蕃茄馅饼，你建议哪种面呢？
- Oh, well they're both exquisite.. - Both it is. Thank you.
-嗯，两种都很美味… -两种都要，谢谢
Now, let's go, baby. It's food time. Bring it, bitch.
现在，快点，宝贝 用餐了，上菜吧，婊子
- Sorry about that. - It's quite all right.
-很抱歉 -没关系
Oh, can I make a special request?
喔，我可以有个特殊要求吗？
Can you bring everything as it's ready?
你可以全部一起上吗？
- Appetizers, entrees, we don't care. - Hey!
-前菜，前餐，我们不介意 -嘿！
- I'll wait to put your order in. - What did I ever do to you?
-我可以等你们加点 -我有对不起你吗？
Nothing, bitch.
没有，婊子
You guys are over an hour late.
你们迟到一个多小时了
- What happened to you two? - So sorry.
-发生了什么事？ -很抱歉
- We got locked out of the apartment. - That's a great story. Can I eat it?
-我们被锁在公寓外面 -真是好借口，可以给我吃吗？
And then Rachel wasn't sure she could leave the baby.
然后瑞秋在犹豫是不是要离开婴儿
It wasn't easy, but it's your birthday and I did what I had to do.
不是很容易，但是今天是你生日 我做了我必须要做的事
And that's Judy over there at the bar with Emma?
那是茱蒂跟艾犸在吧台那边吗？
This is for the best. I'm not distracted, worrying about Emma..
这是最好的方式，这样我才不会分心 担心艾犸…
how she's doing at home, and I'm gonna be completely here with you.
在家有没有事 我得要完全跟你们待在这里
- Oh, she spit up. She spit up. - What?
-喔，她吐了，她吐了 -什么？
Judy? She spit.. Judy, look alive, Judy!
茱蒂？她吐… 茱蒂，醒醒，茱蒂！
- Thank you. - Thanks.
-谢谢 -谢谢
Oh, everything looks delicious.
喔，每道菜看起来都很美味
What should I have? What should I have?
我应该点什么呢？ 我应该点什么呢？
Never hit a woman. Never hit a woman.
不能打女人 不能打女人
I know what you mean, this menu's incredible.
我知道你的意思，菜单实在太棒了
Ross bruises like a peach. He bruises like a peach.
罗斯像桃子一样容易受伤 他像桃子一样容易受伤
Okay, I'll have the fig salad and the duck.
好了，我要点无花果沙拉 还有鸭肉
I'll have the soup and the salmon.
我要点汤跟鲑鱼
Remember, whatever comes up first, okay?
记住，先做好的就先出，好吗？
- Hurry.. - Happy birthday!
-快点… -生日快乐！
Son of a bitch!
狗娘养的！
- Where have you been? - Well, we had a little fight.
-你们去哪了？ -嗯，我们刚刚在吵架
I would never lie to get someone into bed.
我怎样都不会骗人上床
You used to tell girls you were a Kennedy.
你曾经骗过女生你是甘尼迪家族的人
Thanks.
谢谢
Thanks. Wow.
谢谢，哇
A little tight, isn't it? Why didn't you get a bigger table?
有点挤，不是吗？ 你为什么不订大一点的桌子呢？
You had a big table but they made you move.
你有订，但他们要你换桌
Shut up, Monica.
闭嘴，摩妮卡
Oh, well, I suppose that Chandler will have the smoked duck.
嗯，我想钱德应该想要点“烟”熏鸭肉
And I suppose that Monica will have the manipulative shrew.
而我想摩妮卡应该想点酥“诈”鼠肉
How did I miss that?
我是怎么没看到那些呢？
- I'll give you another minute. - What, where you going?
-我再让你们考虑一下 -什么？你要去哪？
He said she wanted the shrew!
他说她想要鼠肉的！
Rach, come on, Emma's fine.
瑞秋，别这样，艾犸没事的
You're turning into an obsessive mother, okay? You need to stop.
你已经变成过份关心的母亲了 你要停止这样
You ever hear the story about when Ross' mom went to the beauty salon?
你们有听过罗斯他妈 去美容院的故事吗？
- You mean the willy story? - They already know it.
-你是说小鸡鸡的事吗？ -他们早就知道了
We've been waiting for you for a long time.
我们等你们好久了
- You should order. - That's okay.
-你们应该点餐了 -没关系
- I told the waiter what they want. - Why would you do that?
-我告诉侍者他们要点什么了 -你为什么那样做呢？
Chandler, control your woman.
钱德，控制一下你的女人
Okay, well.. Everybody has ordered.
好了，嗯… 既然大家都已经点餐了
I would like to start the celebration and make a toast to Phoebe.
我想要先敬菲比一杯 来开始今晚的庆祝
- She dropped her sock. - What?
-她袜子掉了 -什么？
No. No, Emma dropped her sock.
-不，不，艾犸的袜子掉了
- How do you know that? - She's over there.
-你怎么知道？ -她就在那边
- Mom's with her. - Mom's here?
-妈跟她在一起 -妈在这里？
I wanted to have lunch with her today. She told me she was out of town.
我今天想跟她一起用午餐 她告诉我她不在附近
She still has not noticed that the baby's sock is on the ground.
她还是没有注意到 婴儿的袜子已经在地上了
It's a good toast.
真是敬的好
Look, will you please get her attention?
听着，你可不可以叫她呢？
Mommy?
妈咪？
Mother.
妈
Oh, for God's sake, Judy, pick up the sock!
喔，天啊，茱蒂，把袜子捡起来！
Pick up the sock! Pick up the sock!
捡起袜子！捡起袜子！
I'm sorry, was that rude?
我很抱歉，这样很没礼貌吗？
Did my little outburst..
我这样的吼叫…
blunt the hideousness that is this evening?
有使今晚 变得比较难堪吗？
Look, I know you have a lot going on..
听着，我知道你们都有自己的事…
but all I wanted to do was have dinner with my friends on my birthday.
但我想要的只不过是跟我的朋友 一起吃晚餐庆祝我的生日
And you are all so late, and you didn't even have the courtesy to call.
你们全部都迟到 而且连打电话告知的礼貌都没有
Well, it's too late now.
这已经来不及了
Phoebe, I don't think that's us.
菲比，我想那应该不是我们
Oh, well, this is.. This is not over! Hello?
喔，那，这个…还没有完！ 哈？
I feel terrible. We should've been strong and left Emma at home.
真对不起她 我们应该坚强一点把艾犸留在家
"We"?
我们？
There are some adult willy stories they don't know.
还有成人版的小鸡鸡事件他们没听过 -
We should've been stronger.
我们是该坚强点
- What is going on with you two? - Well, you see, I'm ovulating.
-你们俩是怎么回事呢？ -喔，是这样的，我正在排卵
Oh, yeah, that's what she says.
喔，是啊，她总是那样说
Maybe you're not ovulating. Maybe it's a clever ruse to get me into bed.
或许你根本没有在排卵 或许那只是要拐我上床的借口
Yeah, Smokey, that's what it was. I just can't get enough.
是啊，烟虫，就是那样没错 我就是很想要
You're not gonna believe this.
你们不会相信的
She tricked me into having sex with her.
她竟然骗我跟她上床
So? You got to have sex, right?
所以呢？你得要做爱的，不是吗？
What's the matter with me? Why am I such a girl?
我是怎么了？我又不是女生
- Okay. That was Mike. - Oh, Phoebe, honey, we are so sorry.
-好了，那是麦克 -喔，菲比，亲爱的，我们很抱歉
You are totally right. We are here 100 percent..
你说的对极了 我们在这里会全心全意…
and we love you, and we are ready to start your birthday celebration.
而且我们爱你 我们已经准备好要开始庆祝你的生日了
You guys, that means the world to me.
你们，这对我实在太意义重大了
Okay, I'm gonna take off.
好了，我要走了
What?
什么？
I love you guys too, but, Mike got off work early.
我也爱你们，但是 麦克提早下班了
Wait.
等等
I'm not the.. I'm not the kind of girl that just ditches her friends..
我不是那种会抛下朋友…
to be with her boyfriend.
见色忘友的人
You know what? I am.
你们知道吗？事实上我是…
Bye, guys. Judy! Bye.
再见，大家，茱蒂！再见
If Phoebe's gone, can we take Emma home?
如果菲比走了，我们可以 带艾犸回家吗？
That's a good idea. Our babysitter just pounded another chardonnay.
好主意，我们的保姆 才又点了一杯白酒
- Bye, you guys. - Bye.
-再见 -再见
See you. Well, I guess it's just us.
再见，我想就只剩下我们了
So, I'm probably still ovulating. Do you want to give it another try?
我或许还在排卵 你还想再试试看吗？
All right.
好的
So, you've never had sex with a Kennedy, have you?
你从没有跟甘尼迪家的人上过床吗？
Actually, Richard was a Kennedy on his mother's side.
事实上，李察他妈妈那边 是甘尼迪家族的人
Why did you break up with that guy?
那你为什么要跟他分手呢？
- You're gonna go do it? - We don't have much time.
-你们不会就这样跑去做了吧？ -我们时间不多了
Once the egg descends into the fallopian tube..
一但卵子落到输卵管…
Oh, wait, oh, get out of here!
喔，等等… 滚吧！
I sincerely hope the rest of your party is returning.
我诚挚地希望你的朋友会回来
No, just me. All alone.
不，只剩下我一个人
Dinner for six for one.
六人份晚餐全给我一个人
Well, you boys are about to see something really special.
很好，你们将会目睹到 一个非常特别的表演
- How was everything? - Excellent.
-一切都还好吗？ -棒极了
The shrew, in particular, was exquisite.
特别是鼠肉，真是美味
I hope you've got some room left.
我希望你还有胃口
Joey. Joey.
乔伊，乔伊
This is the best birthday ever!
这是最棒的生日了！